<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright 2012 smartics, Kronseder & Reiner GmbH

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<document>
    <properties>
      <title>alias-maven-plugin</title>
    </properties>

    <head profile="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcq-html/">
      <title>alias-maven-plugin</title>

      <link rel="schema.DC" href="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"/>
      <link rel="DC.rights copyright" href="license.html" />

      <meta name="keywords" content="alias, maven plugin, maven"/>
      <meta name="description" content="Homepage of the alias Maven plugin. This plugin allows to create alias files with command-line help."/>
      <meta name="author" content="smartics"/>

      <meta name="DC.title" content="alias-maven-plugin"/>
      <meta name="DC.creator" content="smartics"/>
      <meta name="DC.subject" content="Homepage of the alias Maven plugin"/>
      <meta name="DC.description" content="Homepage of the alias Maven plugin. This plugin allows to create alias files with command-line help."/>
      <meta name="DC.publisher" content="smartics"/>
      <meta name="DC.rights" content="Copyright 2012 smartics"/>
    </head>
	<body>

    <section name="alias-maven-plugin">
      <subsection name="Overview">
        <p>
          This <a href="http://maven.apache.org/">Maven</a> plugin creates alias scripts
          from a configurations file.
        </p>
        <p>
          So what problem does this plugin solve? Whenever you type a command in a shell,
          for instance
        </p>
        <source>mvn clean install</source>
        <p>
          you could spare time in simply using an alias like this
        </p>
        <source>i</source>
        <p>
          If you are using license headers that depend on generated build properties,
          you end up with typing
        </p>
        <source>mvn initialize license:format</source>
        <p>
          In addition to the number of characters to type, it is also inconvenient to
          remember the name of the plugin and the fact, that the <tt>initialize</tt>
          phase has to be called before calling the <tt>format</tt> Mojo. So
          an alias comes handy:
        </p>
        <source>l</source>
        <p>
          While creating those aliases in your environment is no rocket science, why
          should we not share our aliases in our team? By sharing we need to add some
          comments so that new team members can figure out what aliases exist and
          what they are good for.
        </p>
        <p>
          This plugin generates shell scripts that set the aliases you define in an
          XML file (please refer to <a href="usage.html">usage</a> for details)
          and adds some documentation to it:
        </p>
        <ol>
          <li>By typing 'h' (default key, can be changed), the aliases with their commands are printed.</li>
          <li>A URL to a team page on the wiki or CMS is printed for further information.</li>
          <li>A report plugin generates a report with the help on each alias to be referenced.</li>
        </ol>
      </subsection>
    </section>

    <section name="Accessing generated Scripts">
      <p>
        The scripts are usually bundled with the artifact of the project that provides the documentation
        (see usage page on how to do this). Therefore download the scripts from the team's artifact server.
      </p>
      <p>
        The scripts can also be made available via the Maven site. Currently we provide no
        Maven plugin to do this. Therefore your use a build script to copy the <tt>alias-scripts</tt>
        folder to the site and add links to it manually.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Supported Script Types">
      <p>
        The following script types are currently supported.
        The script types select the scripts to be created by this plugin and are selected
        via the <a href="alias-mojo.html#scripts">scripts</a> parameter.
      </p>
      <subsection name="windows">
        <p>
          Creates a script for the Windows environment.
        </p>
        <p>
          Use
        </p>
        <source>reg add "hkcu\software\microsoft\command processor" /v Autorun /t reg_sz /d ABSOLUTE_PATH_TO_ALIAS_SCRIPT\aliases.cmd</source>
        <p>
          to register this script to make the aliases available in every opened Windows command shell.
          Replace <tt>PATH_TO_ALIAS_SCRIPT</tt> with the path to the script. <tt>aliases.cmd</tt> is
          the generated file in the target folder that is named <tt>windows</tt> per default.
        </p>
        <p>
          <strong>Please note that using the file <tt>windows</tt> does not work. Rename it to <tt>alias.cmd</tt>
          (or any other file with an extension <tt>cmd</tt> or <tt>bat</tt>)!</strong>
        </p>
        <p>
          <strong>Please note that a relative path does not work. An absolute path to the script file is required!</strong>
        </p>
      </subsection>

      <subsection name="bash">
        <p>
          Creates a script for the Linux Bash shell.
        </p>
        <p>
          Add the aliases to your ~/.bashrc or source it from ~/.bash_profile like this:
        </p>
        <source>source PATH_TO_ALIAS_SCRIPT/bash</source>

        <p>
          Replace <tt>PATH_TO_ALIAS_SCRIPT</tt> with the path to the script. <tt>bash</tt> is
          the generated file in the target folder.
        </p>
        <p>
          For further information please refer to the
          <a href="http://tldp.org/LDP/Bash-Beginners-Guide/html/Bash-Beginners-Guide.html">Bash Beginners Guide</a>.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
